how a Glock works
1 as the trigger is pulled the trigger bar pulls the
firing pin back the connector guides the trigger bar
downward releasing the firing pin and allowing it to
strike the bullet primer the expanding gases from the
powder charge propel the bullet out of the barrel
the recoil forces the slide back
unlocking the barrel as it tilts downward
and allows the extractor to remove the
spent cartridge from the chamber
as the cartridge case is fully extracted
it comes into contact with the ejector and
is forcefully ejected from the firearm
as the slide moves forward
the bottom rail of the slide strips a new
cartridge from the magazine and pushes it up
the ramp of the barrel and into the chamber
the cycle is now complete
and the Glock is ready to fire the next round
as the slide moves back
the hook on the connector is forced inward
this allows the trigger bar to move upward
as the slide returns forward the trigger bar
is then able to retain the firing pin
releasing the trigger allows the
connector to move back into place
again enabling the downward
movement of the trigger bar
the Glock contains three safeties
the first is the trigger safety
the trigger cannot be pulled back
unless the safety is engaged
allowing it to move past the frame
the second is the firing pin safety
the firing pin cannot move past the safety
unless the trigger bar has pushed it up
allowing the firing pin to move past this safety
the final is the drop safety
the trigger bar is held in place by the housing
the firing pin cannot move forward
unless the trigger bar has moved back
and cleared the ramp of this housing
the inside of the barrel contains polygonal rifling
this rifling causes the bullet to spin
providing stabilization throughout
its flight and increases accuracy
cartridges are fed into the firearm
via a spring inside the magazine
when the final cartridge has been ejected
the magazine follower forces the slide lock lever up
and locks the slide back when the magazine is empty